# **Abdullah Esam Mohamed Elkafrawy**

## **Personal Information**

• Email : <u>Dr.Abdullah.Elkafrawy@gmail.com</u>

Cellphone : +966 599 345 502
 LinkedIn : Abdullah-Elkafrawy

• **Nationality** : Egyptian

As a manager in multiple healthcare organizations with over 10 years of experience in both hospitals and pharmacies, I have developed excellent communication, leadership, and problem-solving skills. I possess a deep understanding of the role of the team leader and I am proficient in customer relationship, sales, operations, category management, and supply chain management. My extensive experience in pharmacy management as well as data analysis skills has led to increased sales and revenue growth. As a believer in continuous education, I'm currently pursuing an MBA & I'm well-equipped & prepared to apply my education and expertise to add value to your organization.

#### Education

• The Arab Academy for Management, Banking & Financial sciences.

Master of Business Administration (MBA-Marketing).

• Tanta University, Faculty of Pharmacy.

• **B.Sc.** in Pharmaceutical Sciences. 2012

### **Latest Courses & Certificates**

atest Courses & Certificates	
<ul> <li>Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate.</li> </ul>	
<ul> <li>Coursera, Google Academy.</li> </ul>	2024
• Retail Customer Service Course.	
<ul> <li>Linkedin Learning.</li> </ul>	2023
• Supply Chain Management Course.	
<ul> <li>Linkedin Learning.</li> </ul>	2023
• Retailing Management Course.	
o Udemy.	2023
• Business Analytics with Excel: Elementary to Advanced.	
<ul> <li>Coursera, John Hopkins University.</li> </ul>	2023
• Finance For Non-Financials.	
<ul> <li>Coursera, University of California, Irvine.</li> </ul>	2023
• Effective Business Presentations.	
<ul> <li>Coursera, PwC Consulting Company.</li> </ul>	2023
• Forward Academy by Mckinsey & Co.	
<ul> <li>Forward Program (Foundation – Advanced - Network)</li> </ul>	2022
Category Management Course	
o P&G Healthcare	2022

updated: December 2023

### **Experience**

•	Branch Manager – Al Mujtama Drug Compan	2014~ Present.	
	o Al Mujtama 191 - Al Nahdah	1 Year	
	<ul> <li>Al Mujtama 129 - Al Marwah</li> </ul>	1 Year	
	<ul> <li>Al Mujtama 16 - Al Shatei</li> </ul>	6 Years	
	<ul> <li>Al Mujtama 15 - Al Tahlia</li> </ul>	1 Year	
<ul> <li>In-patient Pharmacist - AL Riyadh Central Hospital, MOH, EG</li> </ul>			2013~ 2014
•	Out-Patient Pharmacist -AlMothalath Health	2012~ 2013	
	Community Pharmacy Manager - Dr. Gehan Y	2012~2014	
•	2 <sup>nd</sup> Pharmacist – Aldaawa Community Pharm	acy, EG	2011~ 2012

### **Soft Skills**

•	Marketing	(Excellent)	Sales	(Excellent)
•	<b>Data Analysis</b>	(Excellent)	Negotiations	(Excellent)
•	<b>Presentations</b>	(Excellent)	<b>Market Research</b>	(Excellent)
•	Budgeting	(Excellent)	<b>Project Management</b>	(Excellent)
•	Comunication	(Excellent)	Team Work	(Excellent)

### **Computer Skills**

•	Excel	(Excellent)	PowerPoint	(Excellent)
•	Word	(Excellent)	Power BI	(Beginner)
•	SQL	(Beginner)	Python	(Beginner)

# Responsibilities

### Managerial Responsibilities

- Provided effective leadership to the pharmacy team to achieve operational efficiency.
- Communicated with stakeholders to report updates that may affect pharmacy operations.
- Developed and implemented a comprehensive standard operating manual to facilitate knowledge transfer and ensure consistent service delivery across branches.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge of relevant regulations and policies to ensure compliance and avoid potential fines or penalties.
- Implemented and monitored safety protocols to ensure the safety of pharmacy assets and report any issues in a timely manner.
- Conducted regular performance evaluations and provided constructive feedback to staff to improve individual and team performance.
- Participated actively in the repeated wasfaty prescription program.
- Supervised the controlled medications team and assured sticking to procedures.

### Customer Relations Responsibilities

- Applied a customer-centric approach resulting in increased customer retention and loyalty.
- Maintained accurate customer records & utilized loyalty programs to maximize sales growth.

updated: December 2023

- Provided patient counseling and education resulting in improved customer satisfaction.
- Handled customer complaints and feedback with a focus on resolving issues quickly and effectively to maintain customer satisfaction.
- Trained and mentored staff on customer service best practices and sales techniques.

### **Operational Responsibilities**

- Implemented efficient workflows and streamlined operations resulting in improved productivity and customer satisfaction.
- Conducted regular inventory audits and implemented inventory control measures resulting in better management of expiry dates and storage conditions.
- Ensured compliance with all legal and regulations by maintaining accurate documents.
- Implemented sanitation & disinfection protocols resulting in an appealing pharmacy.
- Oversaw maintenance and repairs to ensure a well-maintained operating pharmacy.
- Coordinated with suppliers to ensure delivery of products needed for pharmacy operations.
- Trained and supervised staff on pharmacy operations and workflow management to ensure high-quality service delivery.

### Financial Responsibilities

- Monitored and analyzed daily sales and returns to identify areas for improvement.
- Developed a comprehensive purchasing strategy to optimize cash flow and minimize costs.
- Streamlined financial reporting process resulting in more accurate financial statements.
- Facilitated negotiations with suppliers to secure favorable deals and maximize profits.
- Managed inventory levels to ensure timely and adequate supply to the pharmacy.
- Conducted regular financial analysis to identify trends and opportunities for growth.
- Utilized cross-selling and up-selling techniques resulting in increased sales and revenue.
- Implemented financial controls to ensure compliance with internal policies regulations.
- Monitored drug movement data to anticipate potential market shortages and proactively manage inventory levels.

### **Latest Conferences**

•	Diabetes & Ramadan (DAR) international Alliance Conference.	Jan 2023
•	Whole Body Health Symposium by Virtual Medical Academy.	Sept 2022
•	COVID 19 Vaccination Training for Health Workers by WHO.	July 2022
•	6th Prince Sultan Military Medical City (PIOM) by KFAFH.	May 2022
•	15th Jeddaderm by KSAU-HS & MNG-HA.	Feb 2022
•	The Saudi International Conference on Advances in Lasers and Cosmetic	Dermatology by
	Saudi Society of Dermatology and Dermatologic Surgery.	February 2022
•	Management of Covid in hospitals by Virtual Medical Academy.	Dec 2020

# Languages

Arabic (Native)English (Excellent)

updated: December 2023